Steven Basart

Computer Science PhD student

xksteven.com xksteven at uchicago.edu (954) 805-3651

Research Interests

My current research in computer science is in the field of computer vision. I am working on the problem of visual question answering where the task can be described as given both an image and a question to produce a correct answer. Most of my research currently involves the use of machine learning and deep learning methods.

Education

Doctor of Philosophy (Computer Science) 2014 to ongoing

University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois

Bachelor of Science (Biochemistry and Computer Science) 2010 to 2014

University of Miami, Miami, Florida

Courses

Machine Learning

Robot Planning/Al

Computer Vision

Algorithms

Databases

Teaching

TA for Intro. to Computer Science TA for Computational Biology (Fall

(Winter 2016) 2015)

Research Experience

Computer Science 2014 to current

I am working with Dr. Greg Shakhnarovich at TTIC in the

areas of machine learning and computer vision on the problem of visual question answering. I have worked with Torch to create various neural network models.

Biochemistry 2011 to 2014

I worked with Dr. Richard Myers at the University of Miami trying to create a generic genetic therapy via transducible gene editing proteins. I ran western blots, gel electrophoresis, transductions, PCR, and electroporation

Technical

Python Java Javascript / NodeJS
Git / SVN MySQL OpenGL

Projects

OpenGL Renderer

myRenderer

I created a simple OpenGL renderer to render some height maps and draw some objects. Applies simple lighting and texturing.

BattleShip game over internet

BattleShip

I created a simple Battleship game in C that has a client, server interface.